Mary van Kleeck Papers, 1849-1998
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES1906-1961
  - Speeches, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute-Conferences; Oversize Materials]
    - "The Responsibility of the Social Worker in Social and Political Action," notes and typescript, Student Chapter, Social Service Employee's Union29 July 1948 (Box 38)
    - "Are American Natural Resources Being Utilized Efficiently?," notes, Putney School Conference, "How Serious is the Problem of Population and our Natural Resources?," 13 Nov. 1948 (Box 38)
    - "Science, Religion and Social Progress," notes, Boston Community Church12 Mar. 1950 (Box 38)
    - "Governor Dewey and the Legislature By-pass the People's Needs," notes, American Labor Party ForumApr. 1950 (Box 38)
    - "Social Change in the World Today," Episcopal League for Social Action, Seabury House4 Sept. 1950 (Box 38)
    - "For Justice to the Rosenbergs: Implications of the Trial and Sentence for the Social Sciences in the United States," notes and excerpts, The Committee to Secure Justice in the Rosenberg case, New York12 Mar. 1952 (Box 38)
    - Untitled notes, American Labor Party, Kingston, NY1 Nov. 1956 (Box 38)
    - "Social Welfare in the Federal Program," Panel on Social Welfare, National Lawyers Guild23 Feb. 1957 (Box 38)
    - "The Place of the Intellectuals in the Workers Struggle," draftundated (Box 38)
  - Lectures
    - "The Problems of Women's Employment in Trades," student conference of the YWCA, Silver Bay, Lake George, NY 1910 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "Women in Industry," student conference of the YWCA, Silver Bay, Lake George, NY 1911 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - "What is Democracy? Lectures After War and Before Peace," 1919-1940 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "The Ethics of Social Change," Friends' Council of Co-operating Committees, Philadelphia 1937 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Radio addresses 1931-47, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES-International Industrial Relations Institute-Subjects-Radio broadcasts] (Box 39, Folder 5-6)
  - Interviews 1929-53 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Hearings
    - Labor 1916-19 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Women's Bureau 1920 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Economic issues (Box 39)
      - Establishment of National Economic Council 1931 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous 1931-35 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - H.R. 7598: Worker's Unemployment and Social Insurance Bill 1934-35 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - S 3475: Nation-wide System of Social Insurance 1936 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - H.R. 217: Tax Exempt Foundations 1955 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Speaking engagement programs 1906-50, undated (Box 40, Folder 1-9)
  - Books reviewed by Mary van Kleeck 1917-50 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Responses to Mary van Kleeck's articles 1911-13 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Reviews of Mary van Kleeck's books, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES-Russell Sage Foundation-Publicity scrapbooks; Oversize Materials]
    - General 1917-44 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - On Economic Planning 1935 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Creative America, 1936-38 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Miners and Management 1934, undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Technology and Livelihood, 1944-46 (Box 40, Folder 16-17)
  - Research notes, [see also Oversize Materials]
    - Articles 1933-54 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Creative America 1934-46 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Technology and Livelihood (Box 40)
      - Title Page and Contents 1940-42 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence 1940-43 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Forward 1941-42 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Chapter 1, 1941-43 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Chapter 3, 1941-43 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Worksheets for Chapters 6 and 71930-43 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Chapter 7, 1940-43 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Chapter 8, 1940-42 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - Postscript 1941-42 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Unused materials 1942 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Publicity 1944 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Optimum Productivity I
      - "The Impact of Change on Employment and Consumption," Chapter 61933-43 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - "Waste," Chapter 71923-40 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - "Restrictions & Fluctuations," Chapter 81941 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - "Deficiencies in Living Standards," Chapter 91934-45 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - "The Workshop," Chapter 91938-46 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - "Economic Organization," Chapter 10 1928-44 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - "Government," Chapter 111939-45 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - "Productivity for Standards of Living," Chapter 121940-43 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Summation 1940-42 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Administration of Productivity 1940-43 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Machinery 1940-43 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Bibliography and appendix 1940-42 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Statistical supplement-census data 1938-42 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Optimum Productivity II
      - Introduction 1944-47 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - "New Resources," Chapter 11935-45 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - "Electricity," Chapter 21940-41 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - National Labor Relations Board, Chapter 21947-48 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - "The Mineral Industries," Chapter 21941-42 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - "Chemistry & Raw Materials," Chapter 31940-41 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - "Unemployment," Chapter 31938-41, undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - "Construction," Chapter 41940-41 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - "Transport & Communications," Chapter 51940-41 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - "Economic Organization," Chapter 51939-44 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - "Retardation," Chapter 61942-45 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - "New Productivity for Optimum Living Standards," Chapter 71941-42 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      - "Right to Strike," Chapter 81940-48 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - "Deficiencies in Living Standards," Chapter 91937-45 (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - "Hours of Work and Speed," Chapter 111948 (Box 43, Folder 15)
      - Statistics for Appendix 1943-48 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Invitations to speak and write
    - General 1922-53 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Civic Federation of Dallas (Box 43, Folder 18)
- SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES1900-1961
  - African Americans, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Council on African Affairs; League of Struggle for Negro Rights]
    - General 1924-57 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Employment 1925-38 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Labor 1930-42, undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Lynching 1933-35, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - New Deal 1933-35, undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Unemployment statistics 1930-35 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Agriculture
    - General 1932-44 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Migrant workers 1940 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Armaments 1920 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Atomic energy 1945-57, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--National Council of American-Soviet Friendship] (Box 44, Folder 10-11)
  - Automobile industry
    - General 1926-47, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings 1935-47 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Banking 1924 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Barter 1932 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Cartels 1927-36 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Child labor 1905-36, [see also Countries-Germany-printed material] (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Child welfare 1939-50, undated, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Union for Child Welfare] (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Christianity
    - General 1921-54, undated (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Communism 1934-54 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Civil liberties, [see also Communism; Labor; SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--American Civil Liberties Union; Oversize Materials]
    - General 1934-54, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Articles 1935-55 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Academic freedom 1934-40, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Freedom of press and speech
      - General 1934-39 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - John Strachey case 1935-36, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Loyalty oaths 1935-51 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Senate Hearings, Civil Rights Committee 1936-40 (Box 45, Folder 7-9)
    - Alabama 1934-37 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Arizona 1935 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Arkansas 1935 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - California
      - General 1933-40 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Criminal Syndicalism Act 1934-37 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Colorado 1934 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Florida 1934-37 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Georgia 1934-38 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Illinois 1934-39, undated (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Indiana 1934 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Kansas 1935 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Kentucky 1937 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Louisiana 1934 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Maryland 1934 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Massachusetts 1935 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Michigan 1935-58 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Mississippi 1935 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Missouri 1935 (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - New Jersey 1934-40 (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - New Mexico 1935 (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - New York, [see also Loyalty oaths]
      - General 1935-37 (Box 45, Folder 30)
      - New York City 1934-37 (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Ohio 1934 (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - Oklahoma 1935 (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - Oregon 1934-37 (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - Pennsylvania 1934-38 (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Texas 1934 (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - Washington 1934-35 (Box 45, Folder 37)
    - West Virginia 1935 (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - International 1934-39 (Box 45, Folder 39)
  - Coal Industry, [see also Labor-Contracts and agreements; SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Special projects-Employees' Representation; Oversize Materials]
    - Articles and clippings 1926-43, undated (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
    - Bureau of Mines 1932-33 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Coal Labor Board 1934 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Hamilton System of Mining 1934 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Investigation of Conditions 1934-43 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Laws and legislation 1911-35, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Photographs (Box 46)
      - General 1934-36, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Pittsburgh 1934 (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - West Virginia, Consolidated Coal Company 1934 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Progressive Miners of America 1933 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Strikes 1928-36, undated (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - United Mine Workers of America
      - General 1906-30 (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - Contracts and constitutions 1900-40 (Box 46, Folder 14-17)
      - John L. Lewis (Box 46)
        - Articles 1935-46 (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - Newspaper clippings 1935-46 (Box 47, Folder 2-3)
    - Miscellaneous 1930-39 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Colorado
      - Wage reduction 1931-32 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Interviews 1919-1920 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - Reports 1932 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Statistical material 1928-32 (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Trade practices 1931-32 (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Victor-American Fuel Company 1920 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Kentucky 1933-34 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Oklahoma 1935 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Pennsylvania
      - Coal Control Association 1933-34 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Allegheny County, [see also Photographs]
        - General 1931-36 (Box 48, Folder 2)
        - Pittsburgh-Allegheny Coal Company 1934 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Clearfield County 1933-34 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Fayette County
        - General 1934 (Box 48, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence 1933 (Box 48, Folder 6)
        - Newspaper clippings 1934-35 (Box 48, Folder 7)
        - Frick Mines
          - General 1933-34, undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
          - Colonial #31934 (Box 48, Folder 9)
          - Colonial #41933-34 (Box 48, Folder 10)
          - Edenborn 1933-34 (Box 48, Folder 11)
          - Footdale 1934 (Box 48, Folder 12)
        - Miners' Independent Brotherhood 1933, undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
        - Republic Steel Corporation 1934 (Box 48, Folder 14)
        - Workman's Brotherhood 1933, undated (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Greene County 1933 (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - Lawrence County 1934 (Box 48, Folder 17)
      - Pittsburgh
        - Captive Mines 1933-34 (Box 48, Folder 18)
        - Pittsburgh Coal Company 1935 (Box 48, Folder 19)
        - United Mine Workers 1921-34 (Box 48, Folder 20)
      - Somerset County
        - Coal Operators' Association 1934 (Box 48, Folder 21)
        - Consolidation Coal Company 1924-34 (Box 48, Folder 22)
        - United Mine Workers of America 1934 (Box 48, Folder 23)
      - Westmoreland County 1934 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Virginia
      - Coal Operators' Association 1933-34 (Box 48, Folder 25)
      - Benedict Coal Company 1934 (Box 48, Folder 26)
      - Stonega Coke and Coal Company 1934 (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - West Virginia
      - Correspondence 1931-32 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Joint Labor Board 1933-34 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Newspaper clippings 1931-32 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Production 1933-34 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Relief 1932-34, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Amherst Coal Company 1933-34 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Bethlehem Mines Corporation 1933-34 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Hatfield Campbell Creek Coal Company 1934 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Kanawha & Hocking Coal & Coke Company 1933-34 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Kelley's Creek Colliery Company 1934 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Merrill Coal Mine 1931-34 (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - Red Jacket Consolidated Coal Company 1932-34 (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - United Mine Workers (Box 49)
        - Agreements 1933-34, [see also Labor-Contracts and agreements] (Box 49, Folder 13)
        - District 171933-34, undated (Box 49, Folder 14)
        - District 311933 (Box 49, Folder 15)
      - West Virginia Coal & Coke Corporation 1934 (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - Wyatt Coal Company 1933 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - International
      - General 1927-46 (Box 49, Folder 18)
      - Belgium 1922-46 (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - Bolivia 1942-43 (Box 49, Folder 20)
      - Canada 1935 (Box 49, Folder 21)
      - France 1922-46 (Box 49, Folder 22)
      - Germany
        - General 1921-47 (Box 49, Folder 23)
        - Prussiaundated (Box 49, Folder 24)
      - Great Britain
        - General 1922-27 (Box 49, Folder 25)
        - Articles and newspaper clippings 1924-48, undated (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - Communism, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Communist Party]
    - General 1933-60 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Lattimore, Owen 1954-55 (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Countries, [see also Coal industry-International; Oversize Materials]
    - Australia 1927-29, [see also Industrial relations; SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Federal Council of Churches] (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Austria 1946 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Belgiumundated (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Canada 1924-33, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - China 1925-54, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute--Subjects] (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Cuba 1935 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Czechoslovakia 1937-56, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Germany
      - Printed material 1921-55, undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - News clippings 1933-55, undated (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Great Britain
      - General 1923-38 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Delegation for Investigation of Social and Industrial Conditions 1925-28 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Newspaper clippings
        - General (Box 50)
          - 1930-34 (Box 50, Folder 12-13)
          - 1935-43 (Box 51, Folder 1-6)
        - Labor 1929-37 (Box 51, Folder 7)
        - Unemployment Insurance 1928-43 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - Pamphlets 1929-56 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Workers Educational Association 1923 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Greece
      - General 1944-48, undated (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Newspaper clippings 1935-47 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - India
      - General 1930-46, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Newspaper clippings 1939-43 (Box 52, Folder 6-7)
      - India News 1941-44 (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - India Today 1940-48 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Voice of India, 1944-47 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Iran 1943-47 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Iraq 1939-46 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Ireland 1926-44, undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Italy: newspaper clippings
      - General 1926-47 (Box 53, Folder 5-7)
      - Finance 1944-47 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Welfare work 1923-29 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Jamaica 1942-54, undated (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Japan
      - General 1926-41 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Articles and newspaper clippings 1919-48 (Box 54, Folder 1-3)
      - Christianity 1928-29 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Reports from U.S. Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce 1939 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Koreacirca 1950 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Latin America
      - General 1929-47 (Box 54, Folder 7-9)
      - Labor Conditions in Latin America 1939-46 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Lithuania
      - Lithuanian Bulletin 1943-47 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Newspaper clippings and pamphlets 1938-46 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Mexico, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute]
      - General 1930-47, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Newspaper clippings 1933-47 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Poland 1928-48, undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Rumania 1951-55, [see also Oversize Materials--Labor Newspapers] (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Spain 1936-39 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (U.S.S.R.), [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--International Industrial Relations Institute--Subjects]
      - Correspondence 1930-45 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Dialectical materialism 1933-34 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      - Jews 1932-36, undated, [see also Refugees] (Box 56, Folder 1)
      - Newspaper clippings and articles 1927-55, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Pamphlets 1927, 1952-56 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Recognition of 1933 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Russian war relief 1941-43, undated (Box 56, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous material 1931-55, undated (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - West Indies 1940, undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Yugoslavia
      - MvK notes 1946-47 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Pamphlets 1939-47, undated (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - Printed materials 1937-50 (Box 56, Folder 10)
      - Proposals for projects 1937-51, undated (Box 56, Folder 11)
      - Reports and statistics 1942-47 (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
      - Speeches 1944 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Deportation 1940, undated (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Economic Planning
    - Europeundated (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Swope Plan 1931-38 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous publications 1922-46 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Economics
    - Articles and newspaper clippings 1930-57 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Louis Freeland Post, "The Basic Facts of Economics," undated (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Employment Bureaus 1917-20, undated, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation] (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Equal Rights Amendment 1924, undated, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--American Association of University Women] (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Fascism 1933-38 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Great Depression 1930-33, [see also Labor; Unemployment; Oversize Materials] (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Housing in New York 1931-40 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Industrial Planning 1921-42 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Industrial Relations 1929, [see also Economic planning, Australia] (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Italians in New York 1925-28 (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Jewish Americans 1927-33 (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Labor, [see also Oversize Materials]
    - General 1934-54, undated (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Bibliographies 1919-31, undated (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Contracts and agreements 1900-39, undated, [see also Coal industry; SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Special projects-Employees' Representation] (Box 58, Folder 1-3)
    - Hillman, Sidney, President, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America 1940-46 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Legislation
      - General 1925-57, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Wages and Hours Bill 1937-45 (Box 59, Folder 3-4)
      - Wagner Bill 1934-35, [see also Unions] (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Wagner Act 1937-40 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Mooney, Tom 1930-42, [see also Union Men in Prison] (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings 1920-57 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Newspapers, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 59)
    - Strikes
      - General 1912-61 (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - Toledo Plan 1935-37 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Unions
      - General 1921-56, [see also Wages; SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Russell Sage Foundation--Department of Industrial Studies--Special projects-Employees' Representation] (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Interborough Rapid Transit Company 1927-28 (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Maritime 1936 (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous publications 1906-52 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Union men in prison 1936, [see also Tom Mooney] (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Labor Party Movement 1935-44 (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Library profession 1936-40 (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Machine tool industry 1933, undated (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Medical care 1934-45, undated (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Mission study 1907-12, undated (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - New Deal 1933-44 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - North Atlantic Pact 1949 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Nursescirca 1919 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Passports 1946-57, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS--Personal history--Passport application; SERIES II-. CORRESPONDENCE--Mary Fleddérus] (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Peace 1928-51, undated, [see also Countries--Australia] (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Pensions 1932-33 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Pinchot, Gifford 1923-42, [see also Economic planning; Labor] (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Public affairs 1924-37 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Race relations, [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--National Conference on the Christian Way of Life] (Box 60)
  - Railroad workers 1921-40 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Refugees, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES-- American Friends Service Committee; Hospites; Oversize Materials]
    - Czech: Blatny, Fanni 1939 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - German
      - General 1933-40 (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - Newspaper clippings 1934-39 (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - Böhme, Dr. Hildegard 1939-45 (Box 60, Folder 16)
      - Gutherz, Franz F. 1939 (Box 60, Folder 17)
      - Kiser, Dr. Georg 1938-45 (Box 60, Folder 18)
      - Kuczynski, Dr. Jürgen 1935-44 (Box 60, Folder 19)
      - Lenz, Professor Friedrich 1937-39 (Box 60, Folder 20)
      - Lemberger, Hedwig 1940-46 (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - Spanish 1940-51, undated (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - Resettlement (outside the United States) 1938-40 (Box 60, Folder 23)
  - Religion 1922, 1953-55, [see also Christianity] (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel 1952, undated (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. 1936-45, undated, [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE] (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Rubber manufacturing industry 1933-46, [see also Oversize Materials] (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Settlement houses 1906, 1933, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--College Settlements Association] (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Alfred E., [see SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Social Workers for Smith] (Box 61)
  - Social Insurance/Social Security
    - Committee on Economic Security 1934-35 (Box 61, Folder 6-7)
    - Old age security planning 1934 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Bills 1934-43, [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS AND SPEECHES--Hearings] (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Memoranda 1948, undated (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Social Security Act 1935 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Printed materials 1935-49 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - International 1932-40 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Social Work, [see also SERIES V. ORGANIZATION AND CONFERENCE FILES--Social Workers for Smith]